<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/microadventures/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/microadventures/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-01-04T09:17:45+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/microadventures/feed.xml</id><title type="html">microadventures</title><subtitle>My personal website</subtitle><author><name>Marco Barandun</name></author><entry><title type="html">The original Zürich landscape</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/microadventures/upcoming/2023/06/08/pfaffikersee.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The original Zürich landscape" /><published>2023-06-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-06-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/microadventures/upcoming/2023/06/08/pfaffikersee</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/microadventures/upcoming/2023/06/08/pfaffikersee.html"><![CDATA[<p>During this excurion we will go and visit an <strong>iconic</strong> peatbog in the Zürich area. These landscapes were common in Switzerland and in particular in the area of Zürich, however now less than 5% of this precious habitat is still present in Switzerland.
This is a good opportunity for an chilled spring evening walk.</p>

<p><strong>Topic:</strong> carnivorous plants, orchids, moss, landscape <br />
<strong>When:</strong> Thursday, June 8th, 2023 <br />
<strong>Let us know by:</strong> Wednesday, June 7th, 2023 <br />
<strong>Meeting point:</strong>  19:00, train station of Aathal <br />
<strong>Hike:</strong> easy walk <br />
<strong>Organiser:</strong> Marco Barandun</p>]]></content><author><name>Marco Barandun</name></author><category term="upcoming" /><category term="easy" /><category term="botany" /><category term="carnivorous-plants" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[During this excurion we will go and visit an iconic peatbog in the Zürich area. These landscapes were common in Switzerland and in particular in the area of Zürich, however now less than 5% of this precious habitat is still present in Switzerland. This is a good opportunity for an chilled spring evening walk.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The best via ferrata in Switzerland</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/microadventures/upcoming/2023/05/21/cypripedium-copy-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The best via ferrata in Switzerland" /><published>2023-05-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/microadventures/upcoming/2023/05/21/cypripedium%20copy%202</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/microadventures/upcoming/2023/05/21/cypripedium-copy-2.html"><![CDATA[<p>First thing to mention, this excursion is hard. And you do not have to be afraid of heights. But it is <strong>really worth it!</strong>
After Arriving in Monte Carasso, we will take a cable car (students: 10 CHF, adults: 19 CHF both ways included), walk for roughly 15 min. and then we will already start climbing! This is an excellent opportunity to get that winter rust off and get summer sporty for that beach look I know you want.<br />
<strong>Note:</strong> for this excursion we will have to get up early. Sad news, however the earlier we go, the less other people will be there and the more we get done before it gets hot, the better. If we finish early we can go swimming in a river nearby :)<br />
<strong>Important:</strong> should you not have the needed equipment, there is the possibility to rent it there for 30 CHF</p>

<p><strong>Topic:</strong> via ferrata  <br />
<strong>When:</strong> Sunday, April 23rd, 2023 <br />
<strong>Let us know by:</strong> Sunday, April 16th, 2023 <br />
<strong>Meeting point:</strong>  9:33, bus stop Monte Carasso/Urénn-Funivia<br />
<strong>Hike:</strong>   <br />
<strong>Organiser:</strong> Marco Barandun</p>]]></content><author><name>Marco Barandun</name></author><category term="upcoming" /><category term="hard" /><category term="via-ferrata" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[First thing to mention, this excursion is hard. And you do not have to be afraid of heights. But it is really worth it! After Arriving in Monte Carasso, we will take a cable car (students: 10 CHF, adults: 19 CHF both ways included), walk for roughly 15 min. and then we will already start climbing! This is an excellent opportunity to get that winter rust off and get summer sporty for that beach look I know you want. Note: for this excursion we will have to get up early. Sad news, however the earlier we go, the less other people will be there and the more we get done before it gets hot, the better. If we finish early we can go swimming in a river nearby :) Important: should you not have the needed equipment, there is the possibility to rent it there for 30 CHF]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The famous lady slippery orchids</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/microadventures/upcoming/2023/05/21/cypripedium-copy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The famous lady slippery orchids" /><published>2023-05-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2023-05-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/microadventures/upcoming/2023/05/21/cypripedium%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/microadventures/upcoming/2023/05/21/cypripedium-copy.html"><![CDATA[<p>During this excursion we will go in the search of one of the most spectacular Swiss plants, the lady slippery orchid <em>Cypripedium calceolus</em>. These orchids are exceedingly rare and require specific conditions to thrive. Nonetheless, a large population of these iconic plants can be seen near Arth-Goldau after a moderate hike.
An excellent opportunity for a botanical hike!</p>

<p><strong>Topic:</strong> orchids, orchids, orchids <br />
<strong>When:</strong> Sunday, May 21st, 2023 <br />
<strong>Let us know by:</strong> Sunday, May 14th, 2023 <br />
<strong>Meeting point:</strong>  14:45, train station of Arth-Goldau <br />
<strong>Hike:</strong>   <br />
<strong>Organiser:</strong> Marco Barandun</p>]]></content><author><name>Marco Barandun</name></author><category term="upcoming" /><category term="moderate" /><category term="botany" /><category term="orchids" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[During this excursion we will go in the search of one of the most spectacular Swiss plants, the lady slippery orchid Cypripedium calceolus. These orchids are exceedingly rare and require specific conditions to thrive. Nonetheless, a large population of these iconic plants can be seen near Arth-Goldau after a moderate hike. An excellent opportunity for a botanical hike!]]></summary></entry></feed>